Guide to the Ethelbert Nevin Collection, 1834-1980 CAM.NEV.1987.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Materials Related to the Ethelbert Nevin Room, XII.
  - Clapp, George H. to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, May 11, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 802)
    Western Union telegraph.
  - Clapp, Anne to John G. Bowman, Tuesday (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 803)
    handwritten note.
  - Clapp, George to Bowman, John G., May 26, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 804)
    Handwritten letter.
  - Clapp, George H. to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, June 3, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 805)
  - Clapp, George H. to Bowman, John G., June 21, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 806)
    handwritten letter.
  - Clapp, George to Nevin, Mrs. Elizabeth, June 21, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 807)
  - Crawford, Standon C. to Finney, Theodore Finney, February 26, 1953 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 808)
  - Dickson, Lizzie to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, 1935 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 809)
    handwritten original and two typed copies. Includes handwritten poem Love's Rosary dated Dec. 1897.
  - Dickson, Elizabeth to Bowman, John G. (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 810)
  - Dickson, Elizabeth to Bowman, John G., January 2, 1936 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 811)
    two typed copies and a list entitled "Nevin mementos presented to the University of Pittsburgh"
  - Dickson, Elizabeth to Mitchell, Mrs. Ruth Crawford, July 3, 1938 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 812)
  - Dickson, Elizabeth to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, February 5th (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 813)
  - Edwards, George & Company to University of Pittsburgh, September 20, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 814)
  - Ellert, Laurence B. to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, July 6, 1939 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 815)
  - Finney, Theodore to Brunelle, Eugene A., September 19, 1951 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 816)
  - Finney, Theodore to Geise, Dr. John, November 4, 1959 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 817)
    photocopy. Also includes a copy of a memo to Ruth Crawford Mitchell from Shepherd Witman dated Oct. 22, 1959 re the disposition of the Nevin materials.
  - Fitzgerald, R.H. to Schroeder, Frank C., January 22, 1953 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 818)
  - Fitzgerald, R.H. to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, December 7, 1951 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 819)
  - Fitzgerald, R.H. to Schroeder, Mrs. Frank C., April 3, 1952 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 820)
  - Foster, W.K. to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, July 18, 1958 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 821)
  - Geise, John to Hodges, Fletcher, Jr., November 4, 1959 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 822)
    photocopy.
  - Hodges, Jr., Fletcher to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, February 9, 1939 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 823)
  - Hodges, Jr., Fletcher to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, October 4, 1939 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 824)
  - Hodges, Jr., Fletcher to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, November 8, 1940 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 825)
  - Hodges, Jr., Fletcher to Finney, Theodore F., November 11, 1959 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 826)
  - Howey, Walter Read to Fitzgerald, R.H., October 1, 1952 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 827)
  - Hodges, Jr., Fletcher to Geise, John, November 17, 1959 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 828)
  - Howard, John Tasker to Bowman, John G., March 26, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 829)
  - Howard, John Tasker to Stegeman, Mrs. Mildred, April 2, 1935 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 830)
    photocopy with copy of return receipt.
  - Key, Miss to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, November 23, 1951 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 831)
    typed memo.
  - Kipp, Dick to "Frank", Nov. 21, 1966 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 832)
  - Magruder, Kenneth Dann to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, November 4, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 833)
    typed copy. 3 pages.
  - Magruder, Kenneth to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, December 16, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 834)
  - Margueriete to Ruth, December 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 835)
  - Moore, Alvin to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, February 18, 1935 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 836)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Bowman, John G., July 19, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 837)
  - Nevin, Anne to Bowman, John G., July 22, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 838)
    western union telegraph.
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Bowman, John G., August 2, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 839)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Bowman, John G., August 16, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 840)
    tls and one typed copy.
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Bowman, John G., November 14, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 841)
    tls and typed copy.
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Bowman, John G., November 22, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 842)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Bowman, John G., December 13, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 843)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Bliss, Elizabeth C., February 26, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 844)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Bowman, John G., November 15, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 845)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Bowman, John G., September 11, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 846)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Bowman, John G., September 18, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 847)
    western union telegraph. Two copies.
  - Nevin, Alice P. to Bowman, John G., November 4, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 848)
    als.
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Bowman, John G., January 3, 1935 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 849)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Rupp, Mr., January 31, 1935 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 850)
    tls. Notes to Rupp and Bowman.
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Clapp, Mr., March 9, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 851)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Clapp, George, May 1, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 852)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Clapp, George, May 17, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 853)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Clapp, George, May 13, 1933; 73. (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 854)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Clapp, George, June 6, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 855)
    als. includes photo from terrace of Arcadia.
  - Nevin, Mrs. Elizabeth to Clapp, George, June 23, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 856)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Elizabeth to Clapp, George, May 29, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 857)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Clapp, George, June 16, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 858)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Clapp, George, July 9, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 859)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Clapp, George, July 31, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 860)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Magruder, Mr., November 9, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 861)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, August 10, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 862)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, September 8, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 863)
    tls. Photo enclosed of Mrs. Nevin and her dog.
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, September 17, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 864)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, October 1, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 865)
    als and typed copy.
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, October 9, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 866)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, October 19, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 867)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, October 24, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 868)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to ??, November 12, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 869)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to ???, November 22, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 870)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, November 24, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 871)
    Western union telegram.
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, December 13, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 872)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to ???, December 14, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 873)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to ???, December 19, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 874)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, January 3, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 875)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, January 12, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 876)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, January 20, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 877)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, February 1, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 878)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, February 6, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 879)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, February 18, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 880)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, February 20, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 881)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, March 15, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 882)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, March 29, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 883)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, April 3, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 884)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, August 25, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 885)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, September 20, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 886)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, September 20, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 887)
    western union telegram
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, September 27, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 888)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, October 28, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 889)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, October 22, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 890)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, November 1, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 891)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, January 10, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 892)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, January 11, 1935 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 893)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, January 16, 1935 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 894)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, January 27, 1935 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 895)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, March 31, 1935 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 896)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, February 6, 1935 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 897)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, November 10, 1935 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 898)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, February 13, 1936 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 899)
    tls and typed extract.
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, May 3, 1937 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 900)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, May 16, 1937 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 901)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, August 19, 1938 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 902)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, September 11, 1938 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 903)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, June 17, 1938 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 904)
    als. Also a typed copy of Ruth's June 24, 1938 response.
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, March 7, 1939 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 905)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, March 27, 1939 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 906)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, March 14, 1939 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 907)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, April 5, 1939 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 908)
    western union telegram.
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Thornton (?), April 26, 1939 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 909)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, May 19, 1939 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 910)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, May 18, 1939 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 911)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, May 8, 1939 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 912)
    als. Also enclosed is typed copy of an acknowledgement of Mrs. Nevin's letter from Beatrice Doty, Ruth Crawford Mitchell's secretary and a typed list of of materials sent by Mrs. Nevin.
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, June 30, 1939 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 913)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, August 11, 1939 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 914)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, July 19, 1939 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 915)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, August 17, 1939 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 916)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 917)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Shaver, Miss, February 19, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 918)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, March 31 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 919)
    als. postcard.
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 920)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 921)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 922)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 923)
    als. postcard
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 924)
    als. Postcard.
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 925)
    als. Two postcards.
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Shulgold, Mr., January 15, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 926)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 927)
    als. 5 pages.
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to ??? (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 928)
  - Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert to Thornton ??? (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 929)
    als. Includes typed list of materials for the university.
  - Nevin, Doris to Mitchell, Mrs. Ruth Crawford, July 11, 1950 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 930)
  - Nevin, Doris to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, November 4, 1951 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 940)
  - Nevin, Doris to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, September 4, 1956 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 941)
  - Nevin, Doris to Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, June 17, 1942 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 942)
    als. Typed copy included.
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, August 10, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 943)
    two typed copies.
  - ??? to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, August 25, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 944)
  - Mitchell, Mrs. LeRoy B. to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, September 11, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 945)
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, October 7, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 946)
  - Interior Plans, Cathedral of Learning to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, October 17, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 947)
  - Mitchell, Mrs. LeRoy B. to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, October 21, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 948)
  - Interior Plans, Cathedral of Learning, to McLean, J.E., October 28, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 949)
  - ??? to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, November 10, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 950)
  - Interior Plans, Cathedral of Learning to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, November 20, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 951)
  - Interior Plans, Cathedral of Learning, to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, December 16, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 952)
  - Interior Plans, Cathedral of Learning, to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, January 8, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 953)
  - Interior Plans, Cathedral of Learning, to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, January 16, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 954)
  - ??? to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, January 16, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 955)
  - Interior Plans, Cathedral of Learning, to Dickson, Elizabeth, February 1, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 956)
  - Interior Plans, Cathedral of Learning, to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, February 3, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 957)
  - Interior Plans, Cathedral of Learning, to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, March 12, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 958)
  - Interior Plans, Cathedral of Learning, to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, March 23, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 959)
    Two typed copies. Also includes the following typed lists: List of twenty Nevin Manuscripts purchased by Frederic Shaefer for Ethelbert Nevin Memorial List of Ethelbert Nevin's Manuscripts presented by Mrs. Nevin and her friends to the Univ. of Pgh. List of Manuscripts in custody of University not yet purchased
  - ??? to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, September 6, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 960)
  - Interior Plans, Cathedral of Learning, to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, September 10, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 961)
  - Interior Plans, Cathedral of Learning, to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, September 17, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 962)
    two typed copies. Also includes typed copy of Mrs. Ethelbert Nevin's letter to Dr. Bowman dated Sept. 11, 1934, which is referenced in this letter.
  - Interior Plans, Cathedral of Learning, to Edwards, George & Company, September 19, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 963)
  - Interior Plans, Cathedral of Learning, to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, September 20, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 964)
  - Interior Plans, Cathedral of Learning, to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, September 27, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 965)
  - ??? to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, October 28, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 966)
  - ??? to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, November 8, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 967)
  - Interior Plans, Cathedral of Learning, to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, January 7, 1935 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 968)
  - Interior Plans, Cathedral of Learning, to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, January 9, 1935 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 969)
  - Interior Plans, Cathedral of Learning, to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, January 14, 1935 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 970)
    typed copy. Includes a listed entitled "Completed list of published manuscripts."
  - Interior Plans, Cathedral of Learning, to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, January 24, 1935 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 971)
  - Interior Plans, Cathedral of Learning, to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, October 17, 1933 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 972)
  - Interior Plans, Cathedral of Learning, to Edwards, George & Company, September 19, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 973)
    typed letter. Includes list entitled "List of Manuscripts returned to Mrs. Nevin September 1934."
  - Interior Plans, Cathedral of Learning, to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, September 20, 1934 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 974)
    typed copy. Includes list entitled "List of Manuscripts returned to Mrs. Nevin, September 1934."
  - ??? to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, November 29, 1935 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 975)
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, February 10, 1936 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 976)
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, April 30, 1937 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 977)
    typed copy. Includes copy of letter from Mrs. Ethelbert Nevin to Mrs. Tabor (TLS) dated April 21, 1937, a copy of a letter from Elizabeth Keeney to Mrs. Nevin dated April 15th (typed copy), and a copy of a letter from Bayard Christy to Mrs. Nevin dated March 22, 1937.
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, to Dickson, Miss Elizabeth, June 24, 1937; 187 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 978)
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, May 20, 1937 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 979)
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, to Peery, Rob Roy, June 29, 1937 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 980)
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford to Peery, Rob Roy, July 21, 1937 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 981)
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, to Theodore Presser Co., October 28, 1937 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 982)
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, to Dickson, Miss Elizabeth, April 1, 1938 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 983)
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford to Nevin, Mrs. Elizabeth, December 19, 1938 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 984)
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, March 8, 1939 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 985)
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, March 8, 1939 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 986)
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, March 15, 1939 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 987)
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, March 30, 1939 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 988)
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, April 4, 1939 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 989)
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford to Doty, Mrs. Beatrice, April 10, 1939 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 990)
  - ??? to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, April 12, 1939 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 991)
  - ??? to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, May 19, 1939 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 992)
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, June 26, 1939 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 993)
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford to Ellert, Mr. Laurence B., July 14, 1939 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 994)
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, August 9, 1939 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 995)
  - ??? to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, August 14, 1939 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 996)
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, August 24, 1939 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 997)
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford to Hodges, Jr., Fletcher, October 10, 1939 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 998)
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, October 31, 1939 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 999)
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford to Boll, Miss Elorie, January 15, 1940 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 1000)
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford to Nevin, Mrs. Ethelbert, June 15, 1940 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 1001)
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford to Black, Miss Dorothea, June 25, 1942 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 1002)
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford to Nevin, Miss Doris, July 15, 1942 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 1003)
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford to Robinson, A.L., April 10, 1950 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 1004)
    typed copy. Includes a tls from A.L. Robinson dated March 21, 1950 that the letter is in response to.
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford to Nevin, Miss Doris, October 3, 1951 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 1005)
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford to Nevin, Miss Doris, November 15, 1951 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 1006)
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford to Nevin, Miss Doris, October 3, 1951 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 1007)
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford to Key, Miss Jane, November 30, 1951 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 1008)
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford to Fitzgerald, Dr. R.H., December 11, 1951 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 1009)
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford to Schroeder, Sr., Mrs. Frank, February 7, 1952 (File-cabinet 19, Drawer 2, Folder 1010)